HITESH NATHURAM DIVEKAR

Kandivali (E) mumbai-400101 • hiteshdivekar33@gmail.com • 8286619375

Profile

- Python developer with 6 years of experience.
- Experience in developing and designing web application in python , Django, flask.
- Experience of working in an agile environment(Scrum)
- Development experience in the NBFC and fin-tech trading domains.

Skills

Programming & scripting

Python, JavaScript, PHP, Bash

MySql, MongoDB, Apache Cassandra

Repository & Tracker

Database

Git, ClickUp, GitLab, Bitbucket

Web Framework

Django, Flask, web2py, Fast-API, jQuery

Designing Languages

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

lih	PARIAC	204	†AAIC
LID	ı aı ies	allu	tools
		alla	COOL

PyMongo Data Analysis

MongoDB Tools robo 3t,Studio 3T

pandas, NumPy, Scrappy, Matplotlib &

BeautifulSoup

IDE/Editor

Sublime-text, pyCharm,atom,VS-code

Professional Experience				
Aug 2021 – present	Software Engineer, <i>ALKALYME SOLUTIONS LLP</i> Design and developed scripts and web application.	mumbai, india		
Nov 2020 – Jul 2021	Python Developer, DFLTech (Dhanvarsha Finanace Ltd.) ☑ Design and development of API and web application.	Mumbai, India		
May 2018 – Sep 2020	Jr. Python Developer, Track-point <i>GPS Pvt. Ltd.</i> Development and design of web application	Mumbai, India		

Education			
2018	B.Sc. IT, Sathaye college/Mumbai University	Mumbai, India	
2015	H.S.C, Mahatma Phule Arts Science & Commerce	Mumbai, India	
2013	S.S.C, Samata Vidaya Mandir	Mumbai, India	

Projects

AlgoTrading system

- . Real-Time Analysis: Analyze live data to detect buy and sell signals based on predefined conditions.
- . Decision Support: Provide insights and signals to help users make informed trading decisions.
- . Algorithmic Trading: Implement algorithmic trading strategies for both equity and options markets, automating the trading process using python and PHP .

Alternate Data Engine

This project is a kind of artificial intelligence which helps company to approve or reject short term loan in few minutes. On basis of customer's messages which retrieve from android phone using python API.

Real Estate eCommerce Platform

Developed a Django-based platform for real estate brokerage, facilitating property transactions, rentals (including paying guest accommodations for boys and girls), plots, shops, resale, and underconstruction properties. Acts as a mediator connecting buyers and sellers, with a responsive front-end using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

Duties and Responsibilities

- . Write reusable, testable, and efficient code
- . Design and implement of low-latency, high-availability, and performative applications
- . Integration of user-facing elements developed by front-end developers with server side logic
- . Implementation of security and data protection
- . Integration of data storage solutions
- . Performance tuning, improvement, balancing, usability, automation
- . Work collaboratively with design team to understand end user requirements to provide technical solutions and for the implementation of new software features